<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture decisions on Administration Architecture Documentation</title>
    <link>https://ksch-workflows.github.io/administration/09_architecture-decisions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture decisions on Administration Architecture Documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ksch-workflows.github.io/administration/09_architecture-decisions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Backend Technology</title>
      <link>https://ksch-workflows.github.io/administration/09_architecture-decisions/2021-03-05_backend-technoglogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ksch-workflows.github.io/administration/09_architecture-decisions/2021-03-05_backend-technoglogy/</guid>
      <description>Context In order to iterative development cycles for acceptance testing and user experience design, it is necessary provide the software in a publicly accessible domain. Since the instance will only be sporadicly used at random times, having an always online instance hosted on a rented virtual machine would be wasteful.
Alternatives (A) AWS Lambda Pros  AWS offers lots of powerful features to build web applications. The usage based pricing plans lead to fair operational costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frontend Technology</title>
      <link>https://ksch-workflows.github.io/administration/09_architecture-decisions/2021-03-05_frontend-technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ksch-workflows.github.io/administration/09_architecture-decisions/2021-03-05_frontend-technology/</guid>
      <description>Alternatives (A) Apache Wicket Pros  Powerful framework to create Java based web applications. Relativly small learning curve for new contributors. Supports the reaction of a well designed, modular page structure. Very active community. The framework is time-tested and stable.  Cons  Adding pages with highly dynamic content requires JavaScript which is possible to be hooked into Wicket applications but this gets more and more complicated and thus goes against the goal of maximum simplicity of the source code.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>